他在杀害那些在萨洛尼卡审判中
He's killing those who fucked up
陷害你和你朋友阿皮斯的人
you and your pal Apis in the Thessaloniki process.
他是个无名英雄
He signs himself as an unknown hero.
这个名字有记录，但是有人把它撕掉了
The name was recorded, but someone ripped off the page.
当我到达那里的时候，他好像在说“兄弟”
When I arrived there, it was like he said "brother".
他认罪了！
He confessed!
甚至连那个疯子拉杰科都认出了他！
Even that crazy Rajko recognized him!
我要找到那个疯子拉杰科
I'm going to find that crazy Rajko.
我想那是他曾经工作过的孤儿院
I think it's an orphanage where he used to work.
我知道这个地方，战争孤儿之家
I know this place. The War Orphans' Home.
我在那里接到了小佩塔尔
I picked up little Petar from there.
萨夫科维奇先生总是帮助我们
Mr. Savkovich always helps us.
奥布拉德·萨夫科维奇？
Obrad Savkovich?
出来！
Come out!
你有他帮助过的孩子名单吗？
Do you have names of the children he helped?
听起来你好像很怕他
You sound like you're afraid of him.
- 天啊! - 找到她
- Oh, my God! - Find her.
你知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
小心
Beware.
- 小心你? - 尤其是我
- Of you, too? - Especially of me.
要找我的话就用这个
This is how you'll find me.
波多黎各朗姆酒？
Puerto Rican rum?
暗杀行动将在贝尔格莱德进行？
The assassination will be in Belgrade?
上级也是这么说的
That's what the superior said.
你要不要回去..
Would you like to return...
做王子殿下政府的内政部长？
To the government of His Royal Highness?
我们可以联合起来搞垮这帮人
We can team up and fuck up the gang.
现在我邀请你跟我合作
Now I offer you to work together.
为你的兄弟报仇
Let's avenge your brother.
还记得我的斯洛文尼亚朋友，科斯马奇少校吗？
Remember my Slovenian friend, Major Kosmach?
他会帮我们的
He'll help us.
萨夫科维奇不会怀疑你的
Savkovich won't doubt you,
他知道你是保罗王子的卫兵
he knows you as a member of Prince Paul's guard.
这件事极为重要，而且十分紧急
The matter is of the utmost importance and quite urgent.
他们在等日瓦科维奇将军辞职
They're waiting for the resignation of General Zhivkovich.
这就是我们引诱他的方法
That's how we're going to lure him.
我们绑架他
We'll kidnap him.
萨夫科维奇先生，你被捕了！
Mr. Savkovich, you're under arrest!
萨夫科维奇先生要和我一起去皇宫
Mr. Savkovich goes with me to the palace.
他哪儿也去不了
He's not going anywhere.
那些是想杀死国王
Those are the people who want to kill the king.
创造新时代的人
People who want to create a new age.
他们在给你设套，奥布拉德
They're setting you up, Obrad.
清醒一点
Pull yourself together.
雅娜！
Yana!
你还想要点别的吗？
Do you want something else?
波多黎各朗姆酒
Puerto Rican rum.
快点！
Come on!
不应该是这样的
It shouldn't be like this.
我不想这样的
I didn't want this.
随便了
Whatever.
结果就是这样，没有回头路了
It turned out like this and there's no going back.
你在乎这个吗？
Do you care about this?
重要的是他们的计划失败了
It's important that their plan failed.
我不确定他们失败了
I'm not sure they failed.
他们几乎什么都知道
They know almost everything.
- 我觉得结束了-什么都没结束！
- I think it's over. - Nothing is over!
一切都会按计划进行
Everything will be as we planned.
不，一切都会按照你的计划进行！
No, everything will be as you planned!
- 你骗了我，奥布拉德!-波兹达！
- You lied to me, Obrad! - Bozidar!
你说你想报复他们..
You said you wanted revenge on them...
为他们对我和我哥哥所做的一切！
For everything they did to me and my brother!
是的，我仍然想去
Yes. I still want to.
不是这样的！
This is not it!
这些人没做错什么！
These people did nothing wrong!
无辜的人也会死于战争！
Innocents also die in war!
这是场战争！
This is a war!
如果有人应该知道的话，那就是你！
If anyone should know that, it's you!
这是你的战争！
This is your war!
你不记得真正的大战争了！
You don't remember the real, big war!
你太小了！
You were small!
你不知道所有的痛苦，鲜血，死亡！
You don't know about all that suffering, blood, death!
这一切都说得通！
And it all made sense!
感觉就像一种新的、健康的、强壮的东西诞生了！
It felt like something new, healthy and strong was being born!
然后，塞萨洛尼基进程来了
Then, the Thessaloniki process came
我们知道接下来发生了什么
and we know what happened next.
是这样吗，拉杰科？
Is that right, Rajko?
所有那些骗子，分离主义者
All those crooks, secessionists
而奸商们利用了这一点！
and profiteers took advantage of it!
我们这些曾经流过自己鲜血的人，现在又变成了傻瓜
We, who shed our blood, turned out to be fools again.
所以没有回头路了
So there is no going back.
我们欠死人的！
We owe the dead!
你知道我不会让你失望的
You know I'll never let you down.
我知道
I know.
“梭子鱼吃了梭子鱼，但吃得不够”
"The pike ate the pike, but didn't eat enough".
“饥饿是一种痛苦，现在该攻击谁?”
"Hunger is a misery, whom to attack now?"
你知道你必须杀死 Pletikosich
You know that you have to kill Pletikosich.
快点！
Come on!
我们走！
Let's go!
新时代
NEW AGE
修道士的问候
GREETINGS FROM THE MONK
黑日，第二季，第9集
BLACK SUN SEASON 2 EPISODE 09
为什么有这么多安全措施？
Why so much security?
老板说我们先开枪，然后再问
The boss said we shoot first, then we ask.
你是个硬汉，是吧？
You're a tough guy, huh?
新时代
NEW AGE
这将是艰难的
It will be hard.
他们有很强的安全感
They have strong security.
今晚他们的安保会更加严密
They'll have even stronger security tonight.
那我们怎么攻击他们？
Then how are we going to attack them?
我们不会进攻
We won't attack.
我们从门进去
We'll enter through the door.
我们走！
Let's go!
戴维维奇夫人
Mrs. Davidovich.
彼得鲁塞夫斯基教授正在等她
Professor Petrusevski is waiting for her.
- 很高兴见到你-Danica 很高兴见到你
- Nice to meet you. - Danica, nice to meet you.
- 这边请-谢谢
- This way, please. - Thanks.
我们的星相怎么样了，彼得鲁塞夫斯基教授？
How are we doing with the stars, Professor Petrusevski?
他们对我们有利吗？
Are they aligned in our favour?
别开玩笑了，夫人
Enough jokes, ma'am.
随你怎么说，我很忙
Say what you wanted, I'm busy.
你说如果我需要你就打电话给我
You said to call if I needed you.
不，我说如果你找到我感兴趣的东西就来找我
No, I said look for me if you find out what interests me.
是吗？
Did you?
首先，我需要知道我们是否还站在同一边
First of all, I need to know if we're still on the same side.
我们从来没有站在同一边，夫人
We've never been on the same side, ma'am.
如果我想的话，我可以生气
I could get angry if I wanted to.
如果你问起我们的小交易..
If you ask about our little deal...
不，什么都没有改变
No, nothing has changed.
- 告诉我-奥伯拉德 · 萨科维奇
- Tell me. - Obrad Savkovich.
好吧
Okay.
他要去见诺维奇伯爵,
He was to meet with Count Nowicki,
在见过国王之后
after meeting with the king.
他是一切的幕后黑手
He is behind everything.
谋杀和暗杀计划的幕后黑手
Behind the murders and the assassination plan.
萨维奇杀人了吗？
Savkovich kills?
几乎不可能
Hardly so.
我不知道是谁杀了..
I don't know who kills...
但我知道他组织了所有
But I know he organizes all.
所以你想让我代替你去杀 Savkovich？
So you want me to kill Savkovich instead of you?
不，我会摆脱他的
No. I'll get rid of him.
哇，看看这个！
Wow, look at that!
你已经变成了一个危险的玩家
You've become a dangerous player.
我需要你给我更重要的东西
I need something much more important from you.
我听着呢
I'm listening.
萨维奇和他的手下
Savkovich and his men...
他们只是执行者，是可扩展的
They are just executors and are expandable.
但是在他们的背后是想要消灭的力量
But behind them are forces that want to wipe out
这个国家所有值钱的东西，包括国王
everything that's worthwhile in this country, including the king.
说句公道话..
To be fair...
对我来说，这听起来并不坏
It doesn't sound bad to me.
法西斯主义者和乌斯塔沙派在你看来不坏吗？
Fascists and the Ustashas don't seem bad to you?
好了，够了，摊牌吧
Okay, enough with this. Lay your cards on the table.
你想从我这里得到什么？
What do you want from me?
杀死玛丽亚 · 奥斯奇
To kill Maria Orsich.
为什么？
Why?
她是所有事情的幕后黑手
She's the brains behind everything.
这样她就不会先杀了你
And so that she wouldn't kill you first.
除了其他事情之外，是的
Among other things, yes.
好吧
Well...
我低估你了
I underestimated you.
这种情况很少发生在我身上
And that happens to me very rarely.
看来我们还是一条船上的
Looks like we're still on the same side.
你可以在这里找到她
You'll find her here.
再见，彼得鲁塞夫斯基教授
Goodbye, Professor Petrusevski.
不管发生什么，我很高兴遇见了你
Whatever happens, I'm glad I met you.
Dramche 村，马其顿，保加利亚边境
Dramche village, Macedonia, Bulgaria border
天啊
Oh, my God...
孩子，你完全疯了
Boy, you're totally insane.
我什么时候神智正常了？
When was I sane?
我知道
I know.
但那是凯罗老板的女儿
But it's Boss Kyro's daughter.
你告诉我他是个好人
You told me he was a good man.
他不是个好人他是个好人但是..
He's not a good man, he's a very good man, but...
说到孩子，即使是最好的人也会变成最坏的
when it comes to children, even the best people become the worst.
这很尴尬
It's awkward.
扣紧那个钮扣
Fasten that button.
快点！
Come on!
来吧
Come on.
看看它！
Look at it!
马其顿人做得比任何人都好！
Macedonians do it better than anyone!
你可以供应整个美国
You can supply the whole of America.
只要安排好交通工具
Just arrange the transport.
放轻松，一切都好吗？
Take it easy. Is everything okay there?
是的，我会搬到那里去
Yes, I would move there.
我在那儿休息
I rested there.
你有没有注意到村子周围有恶棍？
Have you noticed any thugs walking around the village?
不，他们都是好人
No, they're all nice people there.
你为什么坐下? ! 我应该一个人带着这个吗？
Why did you sit down?! Should I carry this alone?
来吧，拿着！
Come on, take it!
快点，卸下来
Come on, unload it.
将军，我们什么时候开会？
General, when are we meeting?
- 五点-再见！
- At five. - See you!
尽可能制造恐慌，明白吗？
Raise as much panic as possible, understand?
什么？
What?
你有在听我说话吗? ！
Are you even listening to me?!
- 我在听-你在听个屁！
- I'm listening. - You're listening, my ass!
你为什么这么担心? 因为这次行动？
What are you so worried about? Because of the action?
那个也是
That, too. And...
- 博雅纳失踪了-怎么会？
- Boyana disappeared. - How?
她去了疯子拉杰工作的孤儿院,
She went to the orphanage where crazy Rajko worked,
想找点东西，但她没有回来
to try to find something, and she didn't return.
你知道博雅纳..
Well, you know Boyana...
我不会那么在乎她
I wouldn't care so much about her.
她迟早会出现的
She'll appear, sooner or later.
所以你去了格拉夫加查,
So you go to Glavnjacha,
告诉大家我失踪了,
tell everyone that I'm missing,
我身上发生了什么事，你很担心
that something happened to me, that you're worried.
然后去 Prsha 问问我的情况,
Then go to Prsha, ask about me,
让尽可能多的人听到
so that as many people as possible hear that.
这样萨瓦科维奇就能尽快知道
So that Savkovich find out as soon as possible.
仅此而已
That's all.
五点钟到这儿来
Be here at five.
所以我们今晚就要行动了？
So we're going into action tonight?
没什么好等的，走吧
There's nothing to wait for. Go.
不，这是不可能的
No, it's out of the question.
她太年轻了
She's too young.
你说服我的时候我多大？
And how old was I when you convinced me?
- 这不一样!-不，这不一样
- It's not the same! - Well, no, it's not the same.
他们年纪相仿年轻相爱,
They're just the same age, young, love each other,
就像他们应该做的那样
just as they should.
凯罗，我的朋友，对于这种情况我很抱歉
Kyro, my friend, I'm sorry about this situation.
我在这里，我们将解决一切
Here I am, we'll solve everything.
你能解决所有问题? ！
You'll solve everything?!
- 什么?-谁问你了? ！
- Excuse me? - Who's asking you?!
- 你这个笨蛋!-凯罗..
- You, fool! - Kyro...
凯罗！
Kyro!
祝福孩子们吧！
Give the children a blessing!
她已经许配给别人了
She is promised to someone.
你答应给她的那个人呢？
Where is the one you promised her to, huh?
听着如果你答应把孩子给一个我们没见过的人..
Listen, if you promised a child to someone whom we haven't seen...
他们把我们推进这个村子的时候，他至少现在可以帮你！
He could help you at least now when they pushed us into this village!
别这样，住手！
Come on, stop it!
你的名字是 Tzane？
Your name is Tzane?
- 斯坦尼斯拉夫-多美的名字啊！
- Stanislav. - Oh, such a beautiful name!
过来，雅娜，过来！
Come here. Yana, come on!
他们会谈论并达成一致
They will talk and agree.
凯罗，我的朋友，我..
Kyro, my friend, I...
我没有孩子，没有
I don't have kids. I don't.
我一个人都没有
I don't have anyone.
查恩就像我的儿子一样
Tzane is like a son to me.
你没必要这么做
You don't have to do that.
你不必这样对自己
You don't have to do that to yourself.
我不在乎奥伯拉德，他不会像你和我一样看待这件事
Don't care for Obrad, he doesn't see this like you and me.
你为什么要告诉我这些？
Why are you telling me this?
奥布拉德有他的目标
Obrad has his goals.
我花了一段时间才弄明白
It took me a while to figure it out.
你不该杀他
You shouldn't kill him.
无辜的人不应该死去
No innocent person should die.
牧师的血就足够了
The priest's blood was enough.
你无法接受这个事实
You won't be able to live with that.
你认为我们在这之后还有生活吗？
Do you think there is a life for us after this?
你可以拥有不同的生活
You could have a different life.
我做不到
I couldn't.
死人不允许我这么做
The dead don't allow me.
他们想要鲜血
They want blood.
我们不是杀人的人..
We're not the ones who kill...
他们会报复
They take revenge.
我的兄弟
My brother.
英雄
The hero.
他们不知道他的名字..
They don't know his name...
凶手是..
The killer is...
无名英雄
The unknown hero.
一切都还好吗？
Is everything okay?
一切都按计划进行吗？
Is everything going according to the plan?
是的
It is.
波西达，你想让我来做吗？
Bozidar, do you want me to do it?
站起来！
Stand up!
滚出去！
Get out!
醒醒
Wake up.
你没有告诉我所有的事
You didn't tell me everything.
我知道的都告诉你了
I told you everything I know.
相信我
Trust me.
相信你，是吗？
To trust you, huh?
你认为我还能再犯傻吗？
Do you think I can be a fool twice?
你这么认为吗？
Do you think that?
你听到我在问你什么了吗？
Do you hear what I'm asking you?
奥布拉德 · 萨夫科维奇和切切维奇有什么关系？
What has Obrad Savkovich got to do with Zechevich?
萨维奇？
Savkovich?
他是..
Well, he is...
他是孤儿院的赞助人
He is a patron in the orphanage.
他教育那些孩子并照顾他们
He educated those children and took care of them.
还有那个老师，拉杰科..
And that teacher, Rajko...
他会推荐他们，萨维奇会接受他们
He would recommend them and Savkovich would take them.
拉杰科 · 卡加尼奇？
Rajko Kajganic?
是的，他们是这么告诉我的，他是他们的老师
Yes, it's what I've been told. He was their teacher.
拉杰科是阿皮斯的调解人，我记得他
Rajko was Apis' mediator, I remember him.
阿比斯？
Apis'?
哦，该死的！
Oh, goddammit!
塔宁说得对，这是一次报复
Tane was right, this is a revenge.
失败者向胜利者报复
The defeated are taking revenge on the winners.
仅此而已
That's all.
那场战争永远不会结束
That war will never end.
穆斯塔法！
Mustapha!
什么？
What?
你必须救他！
You have to save him!
求你了！
Please!
你想从我这里得到什么就拿什么，但你必须救他
Take whatever you want from me, but you have to save him.
他会杀了他的
He'll kill him.
求你了
Please.
你背叛了我们的信任
You betrayed our trust...
你背叛了我们党
You betrayed our party...
你没有权利要求任何东西
You have no right to ask for anything.
听我说！
Listen to me!
我要离开一段时间，你要对一切负责
I won't be here for a while, you're responsible for everything.
- 你知道怎么找到我吗?-我知道
- You know how to find me? - I do.
你关注米里奇和其他人身上发生的一切
You follow everything that's happening with Mirich and in general.
这里会发生大事,
Big things will happen here,
我们得尽快换个地方
and we'll have to change the location soon.
那她怎么办？
And what about her?
她怎么了? ！
What about her?!
我们都知道叛徒的下场
We all know what happens to traitors.
我们以后再谈，走吧
We'll talk about it later. Let's go.
朱巴！
Ljuba!
嘿，波西达！
Hey, Bozidar!
Stanko 在找你
Stanko was looking for you.
- 他在哪?-在 Prsha 的酒吧
- Where's he? - At Prsha's bar.
等等你没听说吗？
Wait, you didn't hear?
塔纳西耶维奇失踪了
Tanasiyevich disappeared.
Stanko 认为他出事了
Stanko thinks something happened to him.
我听说了塔纳西耶维奇的事
I heard about Tanasiyevich.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你认为这和调查有关吗？
Do you think it has anything to do with the investigation?
我认为这一切都与我们的调查有关
I think it all has to do with our investigation.
有拉杰克的消息吗？
Any news about Rajko?
他也消失了
He disappeared too.
他和博雅纳
He and Boyana.
博雅纳和这件事有什么关系？
What has Boyana got to do with it?
她在我家..
She was at my place...
我给她看了我在 Rajko 家找到的照片
I showed her the photos I found at Rajko's house.
她认出了孤儿院,
She recognized the orphanage,
去看看是否还有人记得他
and went there to see if anyone still remembered him.
什么孤儿院？
What orphanage?
拉杰科工作的孤儿院
The orphanage where Rajko worked.
她去了那里，从那以后就失踪了
She went there and is missing ever since.
那是什么孤儿院？
What orphanage is that?
我没问她..
I didn't ask her...
我真是个傻瓜！
What a fool I am!
那些照片还在吗？
Are the photos still with you?
是的，在我的公寓里
Yes, in my apartment.
我们去那儿吧
Let's go there.
- 为什么?-我在孤儿院长大
- Why? - I grew up in orphanages.
也许我能认出来
Maybe I can recognize it.
快点！
Come on!
乔科大师! 是时候行动了吗？
Master Djoko! Is it time for action?
是的
It is.
准备好
Get ready.
我们必须放弃
We have to give up.
即使发生了这一切，我们的计划也能成功
Even after all that happened, our plan can succeed.
我很确定
I'm sure of it.
我们不了解彼此 Savkovich 先生
We don't understand each other, Mr. Savkovich.
这不是计划成功与否的问题,
This isn't about whether the plan will succeed or not,
问题是太多人知道这是在准备
the problem is that too many people know that it's being prepared.
和我们一起，作为组织者！
With us, as organizers!
我们不能让这种事发生，你明白吗？
We can't allow that, do you understand?
如果你像承诺的那样除掉达维多维奇夫人,
If you got rid of Mrs. Davidovich as you promised,
也许我们的计划会保密
maybe our plan would remain a secret.
我没有义务向你解释
I'm not obliged to explain to you
为什么我要做什么或者不做什么
why I am doing something or not.
我希望你有充分的理由
I hope you have good reasons.
而那个秩序大师会理解他们的
And that Order Master will understand them.
这样的谈话毫无意义
This conversation is pointless.
放弃这个计划是没有意义的
It's pointless to give up on the plan
我们已经准备了很多年了！
we've been preparing for years!
就因为某个前警官
Just because some former police officer
他的同伴听到了什么
and his comrades heard something.
如果刺杀成功了，会有很多种说法
If the assassination succeeds, there will be so many theories
以及可能的罪魁祸首,
and possible culprits,
我们只是众多选择中的一个
that we'll be just one of many options.
是的，你说得很好
Yes, you said that well.
如果刺杀成功
If the assassination succeeds.
我们从一开始就接受了这种风险
We accepted that risk from the very beginning.
我愿意为此献出我的生命
And I am ready to give my life for that.
我会考虑的
I'll think about it.
明天之前什么也别做
Don't do anything until tomorrow.
没什么！
Nothing!
我会打电话给你
I'll call you.
DALMATIA 南斯拉夫王国
HVAR, DALMATIA KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA
米里奇先生恐怕
Mr. Mirich, I am afraid
我对你的建议有否定的答复
I have a negative answer to your proposal.
除非..
Unless...
除非事情的安排完全不同
Unless things are set up quite differently.
我不明白
I don't understand.
你不知道？
You don't?
圣经上说,
The Bible says,
“聪明人打你，胜过愚蠢人抚摸你”
"It's better for the wise to beat you than for the fool to caress you".
我们的教会已经像这样持续了将近两千年
Our church has lasted like this for almost two thousand years.
你看..
You see...
我们的日科维奇不管他是什么样的人,
Our Zhivkovich, whatever he's like,
是我们都知道的系统的一部分,
is a part of the system we all know,
他忠实地服务于这个系统
and he faithfully serves that system.
但是萨维奇
But Savkovich...
想要摧毁那个系统，然后放火烧了它
wants to destroy that system and set it on fire.
在那火焰中,
And in that flame,
我们都可以消失
we could all disappear.
但如果我们把火灭了,
But if we put out that flame,
我们的合作是可能的
our cooperation would be possible.
下次见，米里奇先生
See you next time, Mr. Mirich.
下次见
See you next time.
保罗 · 贝尔格莱德王子的住所，南斯拉夫王国
THE RESIDENCE OF PRINCE PAUL BELGRADE, KINGDOM OF YUGOSLAVIA
我没想到你会来，将军
I didn't expect you, general.
王子，很抱歉打扰你,
Prince, I'm sorry to bother you,
但是恐怕事情非常紧急
but I'm afraid the matter is quite urgent.
什么事这么急？
What's urgent?
你知道新时代
You know the New Age
长期以来一直在对我进行一场肮脏的运动
has been waging a dirty campaign against me for a long time.
你听说工作室里发生的事了
You heard what happened in the atelier.
恐怕在这种情况下
I am afraid that in such circumstances
我别无选择，只能辞职
I have no choice but to resign.
日夫科维奇先生
Mr. Zhivkovich...
我们喝一杯吧
Let's have a drink.
让我们假设..
Let's pretend...
你什么都没说
You didn't say anything.
但是，王子，我是认真的
But, prince, I am quite serious.
我也是
Me, too.
我不希望你离开，将军
I don't want you to leave, general.
我们比以往任何时候都需要你
We need you more than ever.
我不明白
I don't understand.
如果有人知道
If anyone is aware
这个国家的生存有多大的问题,
of how much the survival of this country is in question,
那就只有你和我了
then it's you and me.
我们正在打一场已经输掉的战斗
We are fighting an already lost battle.
南斯拉夫诞生了，不管它是什么,
Yugoslavia is born and whatever it is,
我们别无选择，只能领导它
we have no choice but to lead it.
而且..
Besides...
我也担心我弟弟的未来
I'm also worried about my brother's future.
你知道他有多少敌人,
You know how many enemies he has,
如果他出了什么事..
and if something happens to him...
南斯拉夫必须生存下去
Yugoslavia must survive.
至少在一段时间内
At least for a while.
我到底该做些什么？
And what exactly is expected of me?
你是这个国家的必需品
You're necessary to this country.
是时候建立新的联盟了,
It's time to create new alliances,
更新已经破裂的关系
to renew broken ties
如果发生灾难..
and, if a catastrophe occurs...
为了确保它之后的生活
To secure life after it.
这就是我们的任务
That is our task.
我希望我说得够清楚了
I hope I was clear.
安琪！
Angelche!
燧发枪
Flintlock.
我女儿要结婚了！
My daughter is getting married!
庆祝活动开始！
Let the celebrations begin!
亲爱的
My dear.
爸爸！
Dad!
- 米兰!-好的，好的..
- Milan! - Okay, okay...
不，别..
No, don't...
别这样，住手！
Come on, stop it!
去那里拥抱亚娜！
Go there and hug Yana!
我想我知道我们接下来要做什么了
I think I know what we're going to do next.
暂时别管它
Leave it, for now.
我们先喝杯咖啡，然后再想办法
We'll have coffee first, then we'll come up with something.
波西达，在外面等我
Bozidar, wait for me outside.
萨沃奇先生
Mr. Savkovich...
如你所说，我们已经加强了安全,
As you said, we have strengthened the security,
我们已经武装了那些人..
we've armed the guys...
我们会遇到什么问题吗？
Do we expect any problems?
从米里奇？
From Mirich?
如果米里奇决定攻击我，你认为他会签约吗？
Do you think that Mirich would have signed if he had decided to attack me?
什么？
Huh?
我对此表示怀疑
I doubt it.
不管怎样，做好万全准备
Anyway, be prepared for anything.
明白了吗？
Is that clear?
警报器只有在有电的情况下才能工作
The alarm only works if there is electricity.
他们并不完全依赖他,
They don't rely on him completely,
到处都是警卫
security is everywhere on guard.
入口处的这些呢？
And these at the entrance?
我说放哨，你在军队里服过役吗？
I said on guard. Did you serve in the army?
吉普赛人不应征入伍
Gypsies aren't drafted into the army.
他们的手机在哪里？
Where are their phones?
一个在主任办公室，另一个在理工学院
One is in the director's office, and the other is at the polytechnic.
太好了
Great.
Trnavatz! 买两套男士西装
Trnavatz! Get two gentleman's suits.
我们得先找两位先生
We have to get two gentlemen first.
我们会的，你是克鲁姆先生，对吧？
We will. You're Mr. Krume, right?
- 是的-很高兴见到你
- Yes. - Nice to meet you.
- 尼什基!-什么事？
- Nishky! - Yes?
我希望你成为一个绅士
I want you to be a gentleman.
- 我?-他? ！
- Me? - He?!
- 怎么了?-你不能做个绅士
- What's the problem? - You can't be a gentleman.
- 在贝尔格莱德待了13年-你不可能是个绅士
- 13 years in Belgrade. - You can't be a gentleman.
哦，住手! Chira！
Oh, stop it! Chira!
给 Trnavatz 和 Gezim 找两套工作服
Find two work suits for Trnavatz and Gezim.
快点！
Come on!
我已经在这里住了13年了，拜托！
I've been living here for 13 years, come on!
我告诉过你一百次了，我不在的时候不要来
I've told you a hundred times not to come when I'm not here.
发生了什么？
What happened?
你有生命危险,
Your life is in danger,
你没多少时间了，你是下一个受害者
you don't have much time, you're the next victim.
- 你怎么知道的?-博雅纳告诉我的
- How do you know that? - Boyana told me.
- 博雅纳?-是的，你的博雅纳
- Boyana? - Yes, your Boyana.
他们抓住了她
They caught her.
谁抓住她的？
Who caught her?
女名女子名
Mustapha.
穆斯塔法 · 戈卢布里奇和他的共产主义者
Mustapha Golubich and his communists.
他们把她关在天文台
They keep her locked up in the observatory.
快去救她，她知道谁想杀你
Go, save her, she knows who wants to kill you.
穆斯塔法 · 戈卢比奇和博雅纳
Mustapha Golubich and Boyana...
你在说什么? ！
What are you talking about?!
为什么? ！
How come?!
为什么？
How come?
为什么? ！
How come?!
他们是多年的情人
They've been lovers for years.
她为他工作，和他做爱，她爱他！
She works for him, fucks him, she loves him!
现在你知道博雅纳是谁了
Now you know who Boyana is.
他是个非常非常危险的人
He's a very, very dangerous man.
他不原谅背叛，而她背叛了他
He doesn't forgive betrayal, and she betrayed him.
你和 Golubich 有什么关系？
And what do you have with Golubich?
说来话长，现在已经不重要了
It's a long story and it doesn't matter now.
你现在该走了，你没有多少时间了
You should go now, you don't have much time.
我也没有
I don't have it, either.
我必须趁我还能走的时候离开
I have to get away while I still can.
你为什么要告诉我这些？
Why did you tell me all this?
如果我不告诉你，你会恨我的
You would hate me if I didn't tell you.
如果她出了什么事如果我知道..
If something happened to her and if I knew that...
你知道我不会恨你的
You know I couldn't hate you.
哦，是的..
Oh, yes...
你可以
You could.
你爱她
You love her.
你总是这样
You always did.
你得帮帮我
You have to help me.
你有没有觉得所有人都背叛了你？
Have you ever felt like everyone betrayed you?
就像你在这个世界上是孤独的？
Like you're alone in the whole world?
我有
I have.
我的一生
My whole life.
我也是
Me, too.
波西达..
Bozidar...
你愿意做我的朋友吗？
Would you be my friend?
很抱歉把你牵扯进来
Sorry to drag you into this.
你去找塔纳
You'll go to Tane...
告诉他我今晚不去了
And tell him I won't come tonight.
他还活着？
He's alive?
是的，他正在准备一个行动每个人都在 Yataghan 的贫民窟
Yes, he's preparing an action. Everyone is in the Yataghan slum.
我得去救博雅娜，她被绑架了
I have to save Boyana, she's been kidnapped.
给你
Here.
干杯！
Cheers!
谢谢你
Thank you.
嘿，迪塞尔！
Hey, Diesel!
你确定吗？
Are you sure about this?
关于什么？
About what?
一旦一个女人骑在你的背上，就没有回头路了
Once a woman gets on your back, there's no coming back.
如果可以的话，我愿意娶她三次
I'd marry her three times if I could.
快点，帮我把这个扣上
Come on, button this up for me.
我希望我爸爸是保罗王子,
I would like my dad to be Prince Paul,
不是尼什的工匠
not some craftsman from Nish.
你知道我父母没有结婚吗？
Did you know that my parents never got married?
为什么？
How come?
他们没能挺过来
They didn't make it.
就在 Draginya 生下我的时候，我父亲去世了
Just when Draginya gave birth to me, my father died.
我从没见过他
I've never met him.
对不起
I'm sorry.
不用道歉
Don't be sorry.
这就是战争..
That's war...
必须是这样
It had to be like that.
你说得对
You're right.
我想看看 Draginya 看她的时候的表情
I'd like to see Draginya's face when she looks at her.
- 该死!-怎么了？
- Goddammit! - What's wrong?
你在哪里找到这么小的衣服? ！
Where did you find such a small suit?!
这是工作服，是工作人员穿的
It's a work suit, it's worn by people who work.
这就是为什么他们很瘦，你知道，因为他们工作
That's why they're skinny, you know, because they work.
安静! 你们两个! 小声点！
Quiet! You two! Keep it down!
你说她真的很漂亮？
She's really pretty, you say?
马其顿最漂亮的女孩
The most beautiful girl in Macedonia.
- 她不是妓女?-不，不是！
- She's not a whore? - No, no!
- 是凯罗的女儿-她人不错吧？
- It's Kyro's daughter. - She's nice, huh?
是她的第一个男朋友
Tzane is her first boyfriend.
- 他是她的第一个男朋友?-是的是的
- He's her first boyfriend? - Yes, yes.
Krume! 尼什基! 准备好！
Krume! Nishky! Go get ready!
上尉，你要撇下我一个人去打仗吗？
Captain, are you going into battle without me?
你忘了你是和谁一起赢得战争的，是吗？
You forgot whom you won the war with, huh?
不能忘记，中尉
It can't be forgotten, lieutenant.
但这是男人的事
But this is a male thing.
一个男人的东西，你把这些带走了? ！
A male thing and you took these to go with you?!
你和我需要自己去做
You and I need to go and do it ourselves.
- 你说得对-塔尼！
- You're right. - Tane!
这家伙鬼鬼祟祟的到处找你
This one is sneaking around, looking for you.
让他去吧
Let him.
你在这儿干什么？
What are you doing here?
斯坦科派我来帮你
Stanko sent me to help you.
他没告诉你别的吗？
He didn't tell you anything else?
我告诉过你
I've told you.
他神志不清
He didn't have all his marbles.
首先，他闯入 Glavnjacha 说..
Firstly, he broke into Glavnjacha saying...
发生在你身上的事..
That something happened to you...
你消失了..
That you had disappeared...
然后他站起来说有重要的事情要做,
And then he stood up saying he had something important to do,
我应该来找你
and that I should come to you.
为了帮忙
To help.
他说你会向我解释一切
He said you would explain everything to me.
在我看来不像是他
That doesn't look like him to me.
他已经很久没有看起来像他自己了
He hasn't looked like himself in a long time.
那么博雅娜呢？
And Boyana?
他提到她了吗？
Did he mention her?
没有
No.
好吧
Okay.
拿着这个
Take this.
我们走！
Let's go!
在哪里？
Where?
逮捕奥伯拉德 · 萨瓦科维奇
To arrest Obrad Savkovich.
晚上好！
Good evening!
- 在哪儿，小家伙?-去天文台
- Where, sonny? - To the observatory.
你叫什么名字? 你在名单上吗？
What's your name? Are you on the list?
Stanko Pletikosich 督察我在这里值班
Inspector Stanko Pletikosich. I'm on duty here.
这里没有义务，你要么有许可，要么没有
There's no duty here. You either have the permission or you don't.
这是命令
That's the order.
我得进去了
I must go inside.
只有一个人会死，快点，回去，小家伙
One must only die. Come on, go back, sonny.
来吧
Come on.
- 挂电话-等等别激动！
- Hang up. - Wait, take it easy!
转过身，开始走路
Turn around and start walking.
- 放松!-在我面前！
- Easy! - In front of me!
- 放松点-在我面前！
- Just take it easy. - In front of me!
放松..
Easy...
喂? 奥斯托亚？
Hello? Ostoya?
给你你的车几分钟后到
Here you are. Your vehicle arrives in a few minutes.
谢谢你
Thank you.
塞尔维亚王子旅馆
HOTEL SERBIAN PRINCE
谢谢
Thanks.
不客气，奥里奇太太
You're welcome, Mrs. Orsich.
我不认识你，我不想和你说话
I don't know you, I don't want to talk to you.
一切都很好，我们改变了计划
Everything is fine, we changed our plan.
- 我们不需要出租车-好吧
- We don't need a taxi. - All right.
我叫 Mustapha Golubich
My name is Mustapha Golubich.
我知道了
I got it.
如果你想的话，我早就死了
If you wanted to, I would already be dead.
但真正的问题是..
But the real question is...
- 你为什么在这里?-因为你
- Why are you here? - Because of you.
博雅纳！
Boyana!
把枪放下
Put the gun down.
你在说什么计划？
What plans are you talking about?
女士
Ma'am...
我们俩都没有时间咱们把话摊开来说吧
Neither of us has time. Let's lay our cards on the table.
我们可能有过一些计划，但我们放弃了
We may have had some plans, but we gave them up.
- 暂时的-所以我才来这儿
- For now. - That's why I'm here.
告诉你不要放弃
To tell you not to give up.
真的吗？
Oh, really?
为什么莫斯科对南斯拉夫国王的命运感兴趣？
Why is Moscow interested in the destiny of the Yugoslav king?
莫斯科对一切都感兴趣
Moscow is interested in everything.
尤其是独裁者的命运
Especially destinies of dictators.
他们越少，无产阶级就越强大
The fewer they are, the stronger the proletariat.
你是在帮我吗？
Are you offering me help?
这么说吧我们暂时不会打扰你
Let's just say we won't bother you, for now.
没有
No.
很多人都知道，不可能是那样的
It can't be that way, too many people know.
听着..
Listen...
让他们分心
Distract them.
误导他们,
Mislead them,
让局里和警察认为他们抓到了真正的杀手
let the service and the police think they've caught the real assassin.
你打算怎么做？
How do you plan to do that?
消息将来自乌斯塔沙的一名间谍
The information will come from a mole from the Ustasha ranks.
有这样的人吗？
And there are such?
帕维里奇最亲密的同事在这个服务机构工作
Pavelich's closest associate works for the service.
你只要发布消息,
You just release the information,
局里会立即采取行动
and the service will take action immediately.
在他们处理这些事情的时候,
While they're dealing with them,
真正的暗杀是有组织的
the real assassination will be organized.
我猜你要组织这次假的暗杀行动
I guess you're going to organize the fake assassination.
这不关你的事，以后也不会
It's none of your business, nor will it ever be.
唯一重要的是计划得以实施
The only thing that matters is that the plan is implemented.
你会实现它的
You'll implement it.
谁派你来的？
Who sent you here?
我需要知道
I need to know that.
- 没关系...-有关系
- It doesn't matter... - It does.
这是一个条件，穆斯塔法
That's a condition, Mustapha.
否则，就没有协议
Otherwise, there's no agreement.
听我说，玛丽亚
Listen to me, Maria.
如果她有什么三长两短..
If anything happens to her...
我会找到你的
I'll find you.
老板！
Boss!
来自斯科普里和 Nish 的先生们来了
Gentlemen from Skopje and Nish arrived.
关于什么？
About what?
他们说这和香烟包装有关
They say it's about cigarette packaging.
晚上好，先生们
Good evening, gentlemen.
斯科普里烟草公司 Sotirovski
Sotirovski, Tobacco Company Skopje.
Veselinovich，很高兴见到你
Veselinovich, nice to meet you.
Stojiljkovich Tobbaco Nish Panteley...
Stojiljkovich, Tobbaco Nish, Panteley...
这里，这边
Here, this way.
- 司机呢?-让他等等，我们很快的
- And the driver? - Let him wait, we'll be quick.
我们决定混合马其顿的烟草
We decided to mix tobacco from Macedonia
和 Nish 的那个一起
with the one from Nish
还能做出很好的香烟
and make very good cigarettes.
一切都会很完美
It's going to be perfect.
我解开了
I solved it.
什么？
What?
那个警察... 塔纳西耶维奇
That policeman... Tanasiyevich.
问题解决了
It's solved.
这么快？
Already?
你说你赶时间
You said you were in a hurry.
快点，把梯子拿出来
Come on, take out the ladder.
先生们，你们需要什么包装？
What packaging do you need, gentlemen?
普通的... 香烟
The regular one... For the cigarettes.
标签应该是漂亮的
And the label should be nice.
我们得检查一下电
We have to check electricity.
快点
Hurry up.
- 放下-好的
- Put it down. - Okay.
但这不是我来的原因
But that's not why I came.
我告诉过你，时机成熟你会干我们这行的
I told you you'd get into our business when it's time.
我会告诉你的
I'll let you know.
米里奇正在为你准备伏击
Mirich is preparing an ambush for you.
米里奇？
Mirich?
为什么？
How come?
他和那个同性恋皮塔尔 · 日瓦科维奇合作
He teamed up with that faggot Petar Zhivkovich.
他们会追杀你
And they'll go after you.
新时代
NEW AGE
你需要多重的纸？
What weight of paper do you need?
那么，重量... 我们要..
Well, the weight... We'll take the...
最贵的那个
The most expensive one.
如果你有的话
If you have it.
他在科罗沙克的住处
He was at Koroshac's place.
他试图说服他加入他们
He tried to persuade him to join them.
科罗沙克告诉你的，对吧？
Koroshac told you this, right?
谁告诉我的并不重要
It doesn't matter who told me that.
重要的是他们联合起来对付你
The important thing is that they teamed up to go after you.
他们可能已经在路上了
They're probably already on their way.
所以，我们有最后期限，我们有价格..
So, we have a deadline, we have prices...
你所要做的就是付一笔预付款
All you have to do is pay an advance.
对不起，先生们，我真的不知道这是怎么回事
Sorry, gentlemen, I really don't know what this is about.
你真蠢
You're stupid.
真的很蠢
Really stupid.
你帮了我一个忙，现在你认为
You did me a favour and now you think
你可以用你的小手指把我包起来
you can wrap me around your little finger.
你想除掉米里奇而不是我
You want to get rid of Mirich over me.
有十根电线，我不知道该剪哪根！
There are ten wires, I don't know which one to cut!
那个是电的，你这个傻瓜！
The one for electricity, you fool!
- 不好意思-这是发票
- Excuse me. - It's the invoice.
给你
Here you are.
所有的电都是用来发电的！
All of 'em are for electricity!
然后把它们全部剪掉！
Then cut all of 'em!
先生们不幸的是我们没时间了所以..
Gentlemen, unfortunately we ran out of time, so...
等等，让我们为成功的事业干杯！
Wait, let's make a toast to a successful business!
我遵守了协议中我的部分
I honoured my part of the agreement.
如果你不能兑现你的承诺呢？
What if you can't honour yours?
托马斯维奇，我不知道你在玩什么游戏..
Tomasovich, I don't know what game you're playing...
但我会查出来的你现在可以走了
But I'll find out. You can go now.
这边
This way.
再见，萨夫科维奇
Goodbye, Savkovich.
想想我告诉你的
Think about what I told you.
为了你好
For your own good.
谢谢你的关心
Thanks for your concern.
趴下! 快点！
Get down! Faster!
给你老板打电话
Call your boss.
恐怕你要付出高昂的代价
I'm afraid it will cost you dearly.
我习惯了付钱
I'm used to paying.
再见
Goodbye.
喂？
Hello?
什么时候？
When?
等等！
Wait!
- 还是不相信我?-不知道再说吧
- Still don't believe me? - I don't know, we'll see.
帮我接通 Glavnjacha
Connect me to Glavnjacha.
喂？
Hello?
小心！
Watch out!
现在谁是傻瓜？
Who's stupid now?
萨夫科维奇！
Savkovich!
你准备好参加我的40天追悼会了吗？
Were you getting ready to come to my 40-day memorial?
非常有趣
Very funny.
你是谁？
Who are you?
只是个前警察你不能对我做任何事
Just a former cop. You can't do anything to me.
我可以
I can.
泽切维奇！
Zechevich!
把他铐上
Handcuff him.
丹尼洛，你又活过来了？
Danilo, you survived again, huh?
你并不着急
Well, you weren't in a hurry.
- 我们走!-塔尼！
- Let's go! - Tane!
什么？
What?
我有事要告诉你
I have something to tell you.
我撒谎了
I lied.
我知道 Stanko 在哪
I know where Stanko is.
共产主义者绑架了博雅纳，他一个人去追捕他们
The communists kidnapped Boyana, he went after them alone.
我不能告诉你
I couldn't tell you.
- 混蛋!-我发过誓的！
- Motherfucker! - I was sworn!
我不能，我向他保证过的！
I couldn't! I gave him my word!
我向他保证过的！
I gave him my word!
该死的！
Goddammit!
我们没时间了
We have no time.
我们必须抓住他
We have to get him.
塔妮！
Tane!
我应该开车去亚塔汗贫民窟吗？
Should I drive to the Yataghan slum?
没有
No.
计划有变！
Change of plan!
你不可能知道的
You couldn't know that.
没有人可以
No one could.
我可以
I could.
他就像我的兄弟一样
He was like a brother to me.
看着他！
Watch him!
这边
This way.
把这个拿下来
Take this off me.
我亲爱的马其顿朋友们！
My dear Macedonian friends!
现在..
Now...
我的儿子，Tzane..
My son, Tzane...
只要一颗子弹..
With one bullet...
将拍摄一个苹果和拿起一个戒指
Will shoot an apple and pick up a ring
那会把他绑起来的
that will tie him
为你和我们的亚纳干杯！
to your and our Yana for the rest of his life!
快点！
Come on!
别让我失望
Don't let me down.
举起手来！
Hands up!
- 你没事吧?-没事
- Are you okay? - Yes.
他们抓住了萨瓦科维奇
They caught Savkovich.
他在哪儿？
Where's he?
在车里，泽切维奇正看着他
In the car, Zechevich is guarding him.
还有一个
U.H. JUST ONE MORE
米兰..
Milan...
对不起
I'm sorry.
让我把你介绍给我的战友
Let me introduce you to my war friend.
好吧
Okay.
你见到我很惊讶吗？
Are you surprised to see me?